export const booklet_mdsp = [
    {
        choices: ["more than", "approximately the same", "less than", "the same"],
        correctAnswer: "approximately the same",
        question: "When tested in compression, ductile material usually exhibit _____ characteristics up to the yield strength as they do when tested in tension.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Ferrite", "Lignite", "Quinite", "Bainite"],
        correctAnswer: "Bainite",
        question: "The rapid cooling of steel to a temperature between 400 to 800 deg F in enough time, then austenite is transformed into a materials called.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["122.940 mm", "131.204 mm", "112.231 mm", "107.315 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "107.315 mm",
        question: "A solid transmission shaft is 4.0 inches in diameter. It is desired to replace it with a hallow shaft of the same material and same torsional strength but its weight should only be half as much as the solid shaft. Find the outside diameter of the hallow shaft in millimeters.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["11", "21", "12", "17"],
        correctAnswer: "12",
        question: "What is the minimum number of teeth on a smaller sprocket for low speed?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Heading", "Stamping", "Cold rolling", "Spinning"],
        correctAnswer: "Heading",
        question: "It is a cold-working process in which metal is gathered or upset.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Helical spring", "Heavy duty spring", "Conical spring", "Belleville Spring"],
        correctAnswer: "Belleville Spring",
        question: "A cone-disk spring is also known as ______",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Motor spring", "Belleville spring", "Volute spring", "Air spring"],
        correctAnswer: "Belleville spring",
        question: "What type of spring made in the form of dished washer?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["8.72 mm", "12.84 mm", "6.53 mm", "18.16 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "6.53 mm",
        question: "A round steel shaft transmits 373 watts at 1800 rpm. The torsional deflection is not to exceed 1 deg in a length equal to 20 diameters. Find the shaft diameter.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Increasing", "Decreasing", "Constant", "Vanishing"],
        correctAnswer: "Constant",
        question: "In viscosity chart, Raimond-Boyd analysis assumed that the viscosity of the lubricant is _______",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["spring action", "endurance", "resilience", "toughness"],
        correctAnswer: "resilience",
        question: "The ability of a material to absorb energy within is proportional limit is known as",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["6.472 HP", "3.683 HP", "4.395 HP", "5.382 HP"],
        correctAnswer: "4.395 HP",
        question: "Find the horsepowe required to drive a power screw lifting a load of 4000 lbs. A 2 and 1/2 inches double square thread with two threads/in is to be used. The friction radius of the collar is 2 inches and coefficients of friction are 0.1 for the threads and 0.15 for the collar. The velocity of the nut is 10 ft/min.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Fretting", "Carving", "Prestressing", "Friction"],
        correctAnswer: "Fretting",
        question: "What do you call the phenomenon occurring when two touching surfaces have a high contact pressure and when these surfaces have minute relative motion?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["21", "17", "12", "15"],
        correctAnswer: "17",
        question: "Which of the following is the minimum number of teeth on a smaller sprocket for moderate speed?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Euler formula", "Slenderness formulas", "Moment formulas", "Column formula"],
        correctAnswer: "Column formula",
        question: "For very sleder column, what type of formula that is best applied?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["10,010.85 kPa", "11,193.45 kPa", "13,113.83 kPa", "12,420.72 kPa"],
        correctAnswer: "10,010.85 kPa",
        question: "A centrifugal pump is directly couple to a motor. The pump rating is 3,600 liters per minute against a total head of 8 meters of water. Pump efficiency is 65% at shaft speed of 550 rpm. Calculate the torsional stress induced on the 40 mm diameter motor shaft.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Unilateral", "Lateral", "None of these", "Bilateral"],
        correctAnswer: "Bilateral",
        question: "A tolerance where the size of a part is permitted to be either larger or smaller than the given dimension.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["158 mm", "179 mm", "192 mm", "172 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "172 mm",
        question: "A safety valve spring having 9 and 1/2 coils has the ends squared and ground. The outside diameter of the coil is 115 mm and the wire is 13 mm. It has a free length of 203 mm. Determine the legnth of the wire to which this spring must be initially compressed to hold a boiler pressure of 1.38 MPa on the seat of 32 mm diameter. Modulus of rigidity is taken as G = 80 GN/mÂ².                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["465.89 lbs", "305.79 lbs", "426.70 lbs", "347.96 lbs"],
        correctAnswer: "347.96 lbs",
        question: "If the weight of 6&amp;amp;quot; diameter by 48&amp;amp;quot; long SAE 1030 shafting is 174.5 kg then what will be the weight of chromium SAE 51416 of same size?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Impact", "Shock", "Creep", "Load"],
        correctAnswer: "Shock",
        question: "A term used to describe sudden applied force or disturbance.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Hooke&amp;amp;#39;s Law", "Saint Venant&amp;amp;#39;s Theory", "Stress-strain Theory", "Cataligno&amp;amp;#39;s Theory"],
        correctAnswer: "Saint Venant&amp;amp;#39;s Theory",
        question: "The maximum-strain theory which applies only in elastic range of stresses are also known as _______",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["9,450 psi", "10,000 psi", "10409 psi", "8,530 psi"],
        correctAnswer: "10409 psi",
        question: "A railroad track is laid at a temperature of 10 degree F with gaps of 0.01 feet between the ends of the rails. The rails are 33 feet long. If they are prevented from buckling, what stress will result from a temperature of 110 degree F? COefficient of linear expansion = 6.5 x per degree F.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["291.53 mm", "107.42 mm", "109.60 mm", "105.82 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "105.82 mm",
        question: "A 100 mm diameter solid shaft is to be replaced with a hollow shaft equally strong (torsion) and made of the same material. The outside diameter of the hollow shaft is to 27 mm. What should be the inside diameter? The allowable shearing stress is 41.4 MPa?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["465 HP", "200 HP", "493 HP", "365 HP"],
        correctAnswer: "200 HP",
        question: "A line shaft is to transmit 200 hp at 900 rpm. If the line shaft is connected with a speed of 1600 rpm. Find the horsepower transmitted.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["US", "England", "Germany", "China"],
        correctAnswer: "England",
        question: "In what country that present theory of hydrodyamic lubrication originates from?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["12", "21", "24", "14"],
        correctAnswer: "21",
        question: "What is the minimum number of teeth on a smaller sprocket for high speed?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["52.90%", "56.53%", "48.49%", "67.31%"],
        correctAnswer: "52.90%",
        question: "A 80 mm solid shaft is to be replaced with a hallow shaft of equal torsional strength. Find the percentage of weight saved, if the outside of the hallow shaft is 100mm.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Machine bolt", "Stud bolt", "Coupling", "Carriage bolt"],
        correctAnswer: "Stud bolt",
        question: "What type of bolt threaded on both ends and can be used where a through bolt impossible?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Yellow brass", "Commercial brass", "Engraver&amp;amp;#39;s brass", "Red brass"],
        correctAnswer: "Engraver&amp;amp;#39;s brass",
        question: "Which of the following is the high-leaded brass used for instrument, lock and watch parts?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["13.80", "12.58", "10.74", "11.69"],
        correctAnswer: "10.74",
        question: "An engine of a motor vehicle with a wheel diameter of 712 mm develops 50 kW at 2,000 rpm. The combined efficiency of the differential and transmission is 75% with an overall speed reduction of 25 is to 1. Determine the speed reduction of travel of the vehicle in km/hr.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Carriage bolt", "Machine bolt", "Coupling", "Stud bolt"],
        correctAnswer: "Carriage bolt",
        question: "What type of bolt distinguished by a short potion of the shank underneath the head being square or finned or ribbed?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Hydrostatic lubrication", "Solid-film lubrication", "Hydrodynamic lubrication", "Liquid-film lubrication"],
        correctAnswer: "Liquid-film lubrication",
        question: "Which of the following is not a form of bearing lubrication?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["686 mm", "865 mm", "709 mm", "806 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "806 mm",
        question: "An ammonia compressor is driven by a 20 kW motor. The compressor and the motor RPM are 380 and 1750, respectively. The small sheave has a pitch diameter of 152.4 mm. If the bolt to be used is standard C-120 (L=122.9 in). Determine the center distance between sheaves.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Train value", "None of these", "Ratio factor", "MOdular value"],
        correctAnswer: "Train value",
        question: "What is the term applied to the reciprocal of the velocity ratio?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["55,000 lb", "72,000 lb", "60,000 lb", "50,000 lb"],
        correctAnswer: "72,000 lb",
        question: "What load P which cause a total deformation of 0.036 inch of a steel rack which has a cross-section area of 4 sq. inches and a length of 5 ft.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["14,760 lbs", "14 860 lbs", "70,000 lbs", "14,800 lbs"],
        correctAnswer: "14,760 lbs",
        question: "A cast iron flywheel is rotated at a speed of 1200 rpm and having a mean rim radius of 1 foot. If the weight of the rim is 30 lbs. What is the centrifugal force? Use factor C=41.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["9 mm", "11 mm", "13 mm", "15 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "11 mm",
        question: "A steel shaft operates at 186 rad/s and must handle 2 kW of power. The shearing stress is not to exceed 40 MN/mÂ². Calculate the minimum shaft diameter based on pure torsion.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2.417 in", "2.321 in", "1.915 in", "1.980 in"],
        correctAnswer: "1.980 in",
        question: "Assume a factor of safety on the yield point and endurance strength in shear, determine the diameter of the shaft",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Quarter turn", "One turn", "Half turn", "3/4 turn"],
        correctAnswer: "Quarter turn",
        question: "Two shaft at right angesl to each other may be connected by what arrangement?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["35.659 hp", "37.456 hp", "39.566 hp", "40.482 hp"],
        correctAnswer: "39.566 hp",
        question: "A multiple disc clutch of 10 steel disc and 9 bronze disc. the effective outside and inside diameter are 20.32 cm and 15.24 cm, respectively if the axial force of 450 Newton is applied and the shaft turns at 1200 rpm, find the horsepower capacity, assume a coefficient of friction of 0.27.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Hydrostatic lubrication", "Solid-film lubrication", "Elastohydrodynamic lubrication", "Hydrodynamic lubrication"],
        correctAnswer: "Elastohydrodynamic lubrication",
        question: "A lubrication where lubricant is introduced between surfaces which are in rolling contact such as roller gears or rolling bearings?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["14.526%", "13.438%", "12.526%", "15.530%"],
        correctAnswer: "12.526%",
        question: "A single square thread power screw is to raise a load of 70 kN. The screw has a major diameter of 36 mm and a pitch of 6 mm. The coefficient of thread friction and collar friction are 0.13 and 0.10 respectively. If the collar mean diameter is 90 mm and the screw turns at 60 rpm, find the combined efficiency of screw and collar.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["28.25 mm", "28.82 mm", "25.28 mm", "25.25 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "28.25 mm",
        question: "Find the rim thickness for a cast iron flywheel with a width of 200 mm, a mean diameter of 1.2 in a normal operating speed of 300 rpm, a coefficient fluctuation of 0.05 and which is capable of hanging 3000 N-m of kinetic energy. Assume that the hub and arms represents 10% of the rim weight and the specific weight of cast iron is 7200 kg/m^3.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["122.940 mm", "131.204 mm", "107.315 mm", "112.231 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "107.315 mm",
        question: "A solid transmissionshaft is 4.0 inches in diameter. It is desired to replace it with a hallow shaft of the same material and same torsional strength but its weight should only be half as much as the solid shaft. Find the outside diameter of the hallow shaft in millimeters.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["63320 kpa", "40450 kpa", "31298 kpa", "40054 kpa"],
        correctAnswer: "40054 kpa",
        question: "A flange bolt coupling consists of eight steel 20 mm diameter steel bolts spaced evenly around a bolt circle 300 mm in diameter. If the coupling is subjected to a torque of 15.1 kN-m, determine the maximum shearing stress in bolts?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["687.55 rpm", "716.2 rpm", "635.3 rpm", "539.10 rpm"],
        correctAnswer: "539.10 rpm",
        question: "A 50 inches diameter diamond saw blade is mounted on a pulley driven steel shaft, required a blade peripheral linear speed of 150 ft/sec. Motor drive is 125 hp at 1,200 rpm, with 6 inches diameter pulley. Determine the shaft rpm to attain blade peripheral speed required.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["molybdenum", "Nickel", "All of these", "Chromium"],
        correctAnswer: "All of these",
        question: "Which of the following is the most common alloying elements used in cast iron?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Extrusion", "Hot rolling", "Forging", "Intrusion"],
        correctAnswer: "Extrusion",
        question: "The process by which high pressure is applied to a heated metal billet or blank which causes it to flow through restricted orifice.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["4", "5", "2", "3"],
        correctAnswer: "5",
        question: "A flange coupling is to be designed, using 25 mm diameter bolts at a distance of 152 mm from the center of the shaft. Allowable shearing stress on the bolt is 103 MPa. If the shaft is to transmit 5,600 at a speed of 1200 rpm, how many bolts are needed in the connection?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.435 degreee/foot", "0.541 degrees/foot", "0.246 degrees/foot", "0.392 degrees/foot"],
        correctAnswer: "0.246 degrees/foot",
        question: "A steel shaft transmits 40 hp at 1400 rpm. Considering allowable shearing stress based on pure torsion to be 5000 psi, find the torsional deflection of the shaft in degrees per foot.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["75 lb/in of width", "80 lb/in of width", "73 lb/in of width", "71 lb/in of width"],
        correctAnswer: "75 lb/in of width",
        question: "What is the recommended initial tension of the belt?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Creep", "Shock", "Impact", "Load"],
        correctAnswer: "Impact",
        question: "It refers to the collision of two or more masses with initial velocities",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["533 lb", "334 lb", "452.4 lb", "412 lb"],
        correctAnswer: "334 lb",
        question: "A flywheel has a mean diameter of 4 ft and is required to handle 2200 ft-lb of kinetic energy. The flywheel has a width of 8 in. Normal operating speed is 300 rpm and the coefficient of fluctuation is to be 0.05. Find the weight of the rim assuming that the arms and hub are equivalent is 10% of the specific weight.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["39.1 N-m", "32.6 N-m", "38.5 N-m", "34.6 N-m"],
        correctAnswer: "32.6 N-m",
        question: "A single threaded trapezoidal metric thread has a pitch of 4 mm, and a mean diameter of 18 mm. It is used as translation screw in conjunction with a collar having an outside diameter of 37 mm and an inside diameter of 27 mm. Find the required torque in N-m to raise a load of 400 kg if the coefficient of friction is 0.3 for both thread and collar.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["40.2 mm", "37.3 mm", "35.5 mm", "38.1 mm"],
        correctAnswer: "38.1 mm",
        question: "Determine the diameter of the stud bolt that are required to fasten down the cylinder head of a 203 mm x 304 mm gas engine. There are ten bolts on the block. The explosion presure is 31 kg/sq.cm and studs are made of ordinary bolts material SAE 1020. How deep should the bolt be drilled?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["peripheral sides", "twenty times their diameter", "ten times their diameter", "long sides"],
        correctAnswer: "long sides",
        question: "In pure torsion, the maximum stress is at the center of the",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2.25", "2.62", "2.14", "1.95"],
        correctAnswer: "1.95",
        question: "What factor of safety is needed for a 2 in. diameter shaft with an ultimate strength of 50,000 psi to transmit 40,000 in-lb torque.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Stability", "Slenderness formulas", "Euler formula", "Buckling"],
        correctAnswer: "Buckling",
        question: "Which of the following is the type of failure due to unstability?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Dynamic viscometer", "Saybolt universal furol", "Saybolt universal viscometer", "Hagen-Poinsulle Viscometer"],
        correctAnswer: "Saybolt universal viscometer",
        question: "In ASTM standard, what is the instrument used in determining viscosity?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["359 N-m", "432 N-m", "239 N-m", "471 N-m"],
        correctAnswer: "239 N-m",
        question: "An engine of a motor vehicle with a wheel diameter of 712 mm develops 50 kw at 2,000 rpm combined efficiency of the differential and transmission is 75% with an over-all speed reduction to 1 determine the torque to be delivered by the clutch N-m.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Thermosetting", "Tangential casting", "Shell-molding", "Metal-mold casting"],
        correctAnswer: "Metal-mold casting",
        question: "What is the other term used for die casting?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["honing", "milling", "lapping", "hobbing"],
        correctAnswer: "lapping",
        question: "A method whereby a gear is run with another gear that has abrasive surface material.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Relative strength", "joint efficiency", "efficiency", "Performance factor"],
        correctAnswer: "Relative strength",
        question: "In a pressure vessel, the ratio of minimum strength of joint to the strength of solid joint is known as",
        topic: "NA"
    },
] 